

117 Ocean Ct. Boynton Beach FL 33426 | 954-815-1278 | bamers@hey.com | https://github.com/jpbamberg1993

MISSION STATEMENT

"We who cut mere stones must always be envisioning cathedrals." – Quarry worker's creed

HARD SKILLS

I am primary skilled with JavaScript and C#. I love the experience of coding in TypeScript and C#. I am capable on the front end using Vue.js and React.js. I do my best to write semantic HTML and am knowledgeable in regard to CSS, being well versed in modern practices like CSS Grid and Flexbox. When creating APIs, I have extensive production experience with .NET and Express.js. I have also architected a number of production databases and feel confident in my SQL abilities, specifically T-SQL.

Below are all the technologies I have interacted with throughout my career: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, TypeScript, C#, PHP, Java, Visual Basic, Ruby, Vue.js, React.js, Angular.js, Nuxt.js, Next.js, Nest.js, Express.js, .NET Framework, .NET Core, Codeigniter, Ruby on Rails, MSSQL, PostgresSQL, MySQL, Git, Team City, Azure DevOps, Azure, Heroku, AWS, Adobe Illustrator and Photoshop.

SOFT SKILLS

I would say that I am an active communicator. For example, in a project planning meeting I will not hesitate to bring up questions and concerns; attempting to ensure we consider as many edge cases as possible. Or, in regard to emails, I will break the conversation down so that no assumptions are being made and we are being accurate in our assessments.

EXPERIENCE

LQD Business Finance

Senior Software Developer | 06/2020 – Current

- I worked with a team to create a portal in Vue.js and Express.js that would assist businesses with the Payroll Protection Program.
- Used .NET to create an API that incorporated data from QuickBooks into our internal systems.

Third Wave IT

Software Developer | 11/2015 – 06/2020

- Built a portal that would allow corporations to integrate their liabilities and assets into our systems so we could monitor their fiscal health. This used dozens of datapoints and processed hundreds of thousands of records asynchronously.
- Enhanced a portal that allowed business to monitor their CO2 output. This was an interesting project. It was a legacy PHP code base that I slowly incorporated Vue.js into. I also created a .NET API for any new server-side functionality.
- Helped document, maintain and enhance a legacy Visual Basic site.

Rockval, Inc.

Software Developer | 01/2020 – 03/2020 (Part Time)

• Used .NET (running on a docker image) and React.js to begin construction of a portal enabling managers of commercial real estate to estimate the fiscal wellbeing of occupying businesses.

View Thought LLC

Software Developer | 07/2015 - 11/2015

- Created the user interface for the https://www.purplecarrot.com with HTML, CSS and jQuery that called a Ruby on Rails API.
- Built a consumer facing application with Ruby on Rails that provided information and opportunity to the Iñupiat people of northern Alaska.

Real Estate Supplies and Services

Software Developer | 07/2014 – 07/2015

Created our email newsletter and enhanced our E-Commerce CMS.

EDUCATION

Wyncode Academy 2015

• Primarily, I was immersed in Ruby on Rails development. Along with that fundamental education went Test Driven Development, Agile Software Development and Object-Oriented Programming.

PC Professor

Certified Web Designer | 2015

• I learned about fundamental design principles, Adobe Illustrator and Adobe Photoshop.

REFERENCES

- Rob Scaduto | Former CTO | Third Wave IT | rscaduto@developagility.com | 954-401-8322
- Orasio Becerra | Former CIO | LQD Finance | orasio.becerra@gmail.com | 312-401-2233